Yikai Zhang

Shanghai China

(+86) 13553066195 | ykzhang22@m.fudan.edu.cn

BIOGRAPHY _

Yikai Zhang (张益恺) is a second-year Ph.D. student at Fudan University in the School of Computer Science, Shanghai, China. His research topics are mostly around **multimodal learning and autonomous agents**, including (but not limited to):

- Multimodal Representation Learning: Cross-modal alignment and training of multi-modal models.
- Reasoning and Planning: Endowing language models with human-like reasoning and planning capabilities.
- Simulated Environments: Building dynamic and interactive environments for the evaluation of agents.

EDUCATION _

Fudan University (Shanghai) Ph.D. in School of Computer Science

2022 - Present

- Knowledge Works Laboratory at Fudan University
- Ph.D. Advisor: Yanghua Xiao
- Topics: Multimodal Learning and Autonomous Agents

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (Chengdu) B.S. in School of Computer Science and Engineering

2018 - 2022

• School Rank: 2 / 36, GPA: 3.94 / 4.0

EXPERIENCE __

Fudan University (Shanghai)

2022 - Present

- Role: Ph.D. Student
- Topics: Multimodal Learning and Autonomous Agents

ByteDance (Shanghai)

2024 - Present

- Role: Research Intern
- Topics: Multi-agent Learning

PUBLICATIONS _

* represents equal contribution.

- [1] TimeArena: Shaping Efficient Multitasking Language Agents in a Time-Aware Simulation Yikai Zhang, Siyu Yuan, Caiyu Hu, Kyle Richardson, Yanghua Xiao, Jiangjie Chen ACL 2024
- [2] Light Up the Shadows: Enhance Long-Tailed Entity Grounding with Concept-Guided Vision-Language Models

Yikai Zhang, Qianyu He, Xintao Wang, Siyu Yuan, Jiaqing Liang, Yanghua Xiao *ACL 2024 Findings*

- [3] HAUSER: Towards Holistic and Automatic Evaluation of Simile Generation
 Qianyu He, Yikai Zhang, Jiaqing Liang, Yuncheng Huang, Yanghua Xiao, Yunwen Chen
 ACL 2023
- [4] From persona to personalization: A survey on role-playing language agents
 Jiangjie Chen*, Xintao Wang*, Rui Xu*, Siyu Yuan*, Yikai Zhang*, Wei Shi*, Jian Xie*, Shuang Li, Ruihan
 Yang, Tinghui Zhu, Aili Chen, Nianqi Li, Lida Chen, Caiyu Hu, Siye Wu, Scott Ren, Ziquan Fu, Yanghua
 Xiao

Preprint 2024

- [5] SelfGoal: Your Language Agents Already Know How to Achieve High-level Goals Ruihan Yang, Jiangjie Chen, Yikai Zhang, Siyu Yuan, Aili Chen, Kyle Richardson, Yanghua Xiao, Deqing Yang Preprint 2024
- [6] DetectBench: Can Large Language Model Detect and Piece Together Implicit Evidence? Zhouhong Gu, Zihan Li, Lin Zhang, Zhuozhi Xiong, Haoning Ye, **Yikai Zhang**, Wenhao Huang, Xiaoxuan Zhu, Qianyu He, Rui Xu, Sihang Jiang, Shusen Wang, Zili Wang, Hongwei Feng, Zhixu Li, Yanghua Xiao *Preprint 2023*

PROJECTS _____

[1] CuteGPT: Towards a Useful Chinese Large Language Model
Jiaqing Liang, Qianyu He, Yipei Xu, Yikai Zhang, Yuncheng Huang, Wenhao Huang, Xintao Wang, Lida
Chen, Haixia Han, Jie Shi, Tinghui Zhu, Yidan Xu, Shisong Chen, Zhouhong Gu, Yanghua Xiao
Participated in model training and data processing for the instruction tuning of 13B large language models.

AWARDS _____

- First Prize of the Scholarship at Fudan University, 2023
- Outstanding Undergraduates Graduates of Sichuan, 2022

ACADEMIC SERVICES _____

• Serving as a Reviewer of Neurips (2024)